What are the typical uh symptoms for
women when they're low in testosterone?
>> You know, it's I mean, frankly, it's not
dissimilar to men. Uh low libido, uh
decreased drive and motivation. Um I
always tell my patients, you know,
testosterone is kind of the effort and
reward hormone. Um and we we can see, of
course, where where pleasure and reward
maybe gets mixed in with libido. Um, but
but women especially are they're very
good at continuing to do things even
when life sucks. And I think a lot of
men will just play video games and eat
Cheetos for the rest of their life, but
women are fantastic at at continuing to
move on because they're moms and they're
busy. Um, so, you know, I think a lot of
women just have no concept of lack of
motivation truly because they're just so
busy trying to provide for their
families. And um so anyways, when you
really talk to women and you describe a
lot of those symptoms, those similar
symptoms to men, um obviously, you know,
even uh decreased muscle mass, increased
body fat, you know, just that that brain
fog especially, all of those things we
see in men that we're going to see the
same thing in women. I think it's just
it's parceling that out for them and and
kind of showing it to them so that they
understand it.
>> And what administration route do you
prefer for women?
Yeah, again, similar to men, uh, uh,
topical, uh, compounded creams, uh, or
injections. I would, I would argue the
vast majority of my females just prefer
the topical creams. Um, I generally
speaking have them apply the topical
creams intravaginally. Um, I I love
having it applied to a mucosal tissue,
which would be like like the inside of
your mouth or your vaginal canal, for
example. um versus on the skin because
you have so many um you know uh uh uh oh
gosh I'm forgetting the
dihydrotestosterone
uh enzyme uh five alpha reductase uh you
have a much more of those enzymes on
your skin and so a lot of women don't
want to use it uh topically for that
reason because they'll get a little bit
more hair growth potentially and things
of that nature. When you do it uh
intravaginally on a mucosal tissue,
there's just much less of those uh
pretty much almost no five alpha
reductase enzymes. And so we get less of
that dihydrotestosterone
um and a much much unbelievable
absorption. So, we can use far far less
amount of cream and and still get the
same bang for our buck.